おい　早く帰ろうぜ
やべえって　軍の奴らにバレたら
行くぞ　祐二
C'mon.
Let's get the hell out of here already.
We'll be in deep trouble if someone
from the army catches us down here.
We're going, Yuuji.
I don't want nobody to get killed
I'll come and get you, I am always ready to fight
So don't take all of the blame
We were all swept away
I'll come and get you; I'm armed, always ready to fight
Don't take all of the weight
You always do
There will always be something you cannot control
So don't take all of the blame
We will overcome. Your salvation has begun
We're wrong as well
Oh, wait, don't take all of the weight
You always do
No signs, no lights
There will always be something you cannot control
Such a mess all over
We will overcome
Don't kill your hopes
Your salvation has begun
You make me realize who I need
No sounds, no light
Such a mess all over
I'll be there, hold on
Don't kill your hopes
They'll change you somehow
You make me realize who I need
So where are you now?
I'll reach you by dawn
I'll be there, hold on
The shadows appear
Illusions are born
They'll change us somehow
So where are you now?
The fallen angels you run with don't know
I'll reach you by dawn
It is our pain that makes us all human after all
The shadows appear
Illusions so bright
Torn old sepia photographs show
To fall and then just to run
Our fragile preious world
Let them know it is the pain that makes us so human after all
Must discard it, respond to the call
Don't want to deceive me, you follow the truth
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:鱼子酱&paper   翻译:小悠&冰蝶   校对:夜神&Lucifer   时间轴:阿水   压制:久嘉
You found your precious world, but discard it, respond to the call
The Demon
Within
U-Um...
あ…あの…
Thanks for saving me from that vampire.
あの時は吸血鬼から助けてくれて　ありがとうございました
Uh-huh...
I really like you!
あなたが好きです
Please read this!
私の気持ち　読んでください
Well...
いや…
I...
俺…
Oh, my.
やーやー　さすが吸血鬼から学校を救った英雄さん
Just what I expected from the hero who fought off a vampire.
Ever popular with the ladies, aren't you?
モテモテですねー
今度はあの子を泣かせるんですか
Are you going to be breaking her heart next?
What do you mean, "next"?
今度はって何だよ
I've never done anything like that.
んなことしてねぇだろが
Well, I suppose you are a virgin, after all.
まぁ　童貞ですしね
Shinoa, you freakin'...
シノア　てめえ…
But it'd do you well to remember that virginity is evil, Yuu.
でも童貞は悪ですよ　優さん
Take the Japanese Imperial
Demon Army as an example,
なにせ我ら日本帝鬼軍は
where we encourage people
to pursue relationships.
カップル成立を日々奨励してるんですから
Our world was once brought to its knees by an unknown virus.
世界は一度滅びました　それは未知のウイルスのせいで
Strange beasts populated the earth,
and many people died.
突如大地にバケモノが溢れ出し
多くの人間が殺されました
Only ruins are to be found beyond these walls, every inch of them crawling with monsters.
あの壁の向こうは　バケモノで溢れる廃墟と荒野
This is a world no longer hospitable to humans.
この世界は　もはや人間に優しくない
However, we, the Japanese Imperial Demon Army,
ですが　我ら日本帝鬼軍は　残った人間をとりまとめ
will gather the remnants of humankind,
増殖させて世界の覇権を狙う
multiply in numbers, and take back our planet!
Now, give birth!
さぁ　産むのです　増えるのです
Procreate!
Viva la fornication!
ビバ　不純異性交遊
Can I ask you something?
つかさ　一つ聞いていいか
Dealing with that vampire landed me a spot in the vampire extermination unit, right?
俺　この間の吸血鬼との戦いで
実力を認められて　吸血鬼殲滅部隊に配属されたんだよな
So why am I still attending this school?
なのに　なんでまだ高校通ってんだよ
Please direct any such complaints to the LTC.
いやぁ　その辺の文句は　中佐にどうぞ
That moron's never at his office!
グレンの馬鹿　全然執務室にいねぇだろうが
How am I supposed to bring it up with him?
どうやって文句言うんだよ
Certainly not by yelling at me, for one.
中佐のことを　私に怒鳴られましても…
Besides...
それに
Your training for the extermination unit
has already begun.
殲滅部隊の訓練なら　もう始まってるんですけどねぇ…
Training that will allow you
to obtain what you truly desire.
あなたが心の底から欲しがってるものを手に入れるための訓練…
What I truly desire...
俺が心の底から欲しがってるもの
You want this, don't you?
あなたが欲しいもの…これでしょ
Th-That's...
そ…そりゃあ…
This is the demon with whom I have contracted:
私が契約している鬼
Shikamadouji.
「四鎌童子」です
I've been wanting to show you this.
これを見ていただきたかったのですよ
So this is one of the Infernal Arms
that carry a vampire-killing curse...
これが　吸血鬼を呪い殺せる鬼呪装備か
I am a member of the vampire extermination unit, after all.
一応私も　吸血鬼殲滅部隊の一員ですからねぇ
If I had something like that,
I could kill vampires on my own.
それがあれば　俺も一人で　吸血鬼を殺せる
You won't beat them without any help.
一人じゃ無理です
そろそろちゃんと協調性ってものを覚え…
You need to start learning what teamwork—
Shinoa.
シノア
I'll be taking that.
それ寄越せよ
I'm going to use that scythe of yours
to avenge my family.
それ持って　俺は吸血鬼どもに復讐に行く
You can't use an Infernal Arm inhabited by
someone else's contracted demon.
他人が契約した鬼の武器は使えませんよ
Then show me what you've got!
だったらその武器の力　見せてみろうよ
Really?
もう…
Not bad.
やりますね
But fighting against an Infernal Arm with a
normal weapon isn't going to get you anywhere.
でも　一般装備で鬼呪装備と戦うなんて　無理ですよ
Shi.
シーちゃん
That thing's freakin' awesome.
マジですげえな　それ
With a weapon like that, dealing with vampires should be a piece of cake for you.
つーかさ　さっきの武器さえありゃ　吸血鬼なんか敵じゃねぇんじゃねぇか
Oh, not at all.
いえいえ　戦場では　向こうも武装してますからねぇ
On the battlefield, they're just as equipped as we are.
Nothing like the unarmed vampire you fought the other day.
先日あなたが倒した丸腰の吸血鬼とは別物ですよ
They're armed? Seriously?
武装　マジで
That's why Lieutenant Colonel Guren
emphasizes teamwork.
だからまずは部隊で動くための協調性を学びましょうと　グレン中佐は仰っているのです
So you can operate within a unit first.
H-Help me, Yuu!
た…助けて　優君
Yoichi!
与一さん
What now, Yoichi?
なんだ与一　またお前いじめられてんのか
Are you getting picked on again?
Please hear us out, Yoichi!
待ってくださいよ　与一さん
We're sorry for bullying you, for real!
いじめたこと　マジで謝りますから
So please let us be your henchmen!
俺らを舎弟にしてください
Henchmen?
舎弟
W-Wait, I really... Um, I'm just not cut out for things like that!
ち…ちょちょ　ほんとあの　そういうの無理だから
I just can't!
僕　そんなの無理だから
Oh, Boss Yuuichirou!
優一郎の兄貴じゃないですか
It's Yamanaka!
自分　山中です
Yamanaka Satoshi, the guy you saved from the vampire!
吸血鬼から助けてもらった山中智です
兄貴
Boss?
Seems like you've been getting around lately.
ずいぶんと友達が増えてきましたねぇ
I feel rather left out.
私なんだか寂しい
Whatever. You guys were giving Yoichi a hard time just the other day.
ってかお前ら　この間まで与一いじめてたくせに
How could you possibly ask him to make you his henchmen?
どの面下げて舎弟とか言ってんだよ
Th-That's true.
そ…そうなんですが
But we need someone to help us real bad.
実は今　俺らすげぇ困ってて…
困ったらいじめてた相手に平気で頭下げんのか
So you're willing to throw away your pride and beg a guy you made fun of for help?
Seems like delinquents these days
have no shame at all.
最近の不良どもはずいぶんプライドがねぇんだなー
Yuu, you sound like a pretentious twit.
優さん　偉そうですね
We know that we have no right to ask, but...
あんなことしてた俺らが　頼める義理じゃないのは分かってんだ
でも…
But?
でも
Our friend, Yuuji, went inside the Forbidden Chamber and never made it back out.
祐二が　俺らの仲間が
「開かずの間」に入ったきり　戻ってこなくて
The Forbidden Chamber?
開かずの間
I heard that Yoichi had been accepted into the extermination unit, so—
与一さん　殲滅部隊に配属されるって聞いて　それで…
You guys broke into the army's Class 1 Restricted Area?
あなたたち　軍管理下の一級立ち入り禁止区域を侵したんですね
W-Well...
そ…それは…
I don't want your excuses.
言い訳はいりません
I assume this was done as a dare or something, correct?
どうせ度胸試しだなんだと　勝手に入ったのでしょう
Unauthorized entry to that area is punished severely.
あそこに入った者には　とても厳しい罰が与えられます
S-So Yuuji's...
そ…それじゃ　祐二は
Most likely captured by the army.
軍に捕まってるでしょう
No way... Can't you please do something?!
そんな　そこをなんとか…
He might even receive the death penalty.
死刑の可能性もあります
It'd be best if you gave up.
諦めてください
Shinoa, what's this "Forbidden Chamber" thing about?
シノア　一体何の話だよ　「開かずの間」ってのは…
知りませんか　学校の七不思議ですよ
Haven't you heard of the seven mysteries of the school?
人がいないのに鳴るピアノ
A piano that plays on its own, a living anatomical model,
動く人体模型
and a forbidden chamber that you should never open.
絶対に開けてはいけない「開かずの間」
なーにが七不思議だよ
Seven mysteries, my ass.
軍が管理してる立ち入り禁止区域なんだろ
It's just one of those restricted areas that the army manages, right?
そこに祐二君が入って　出てこれなくなった
So Yuuji went inside, and now he's stuck there?
I believe so.
でしょうねぇ
That chamber is actually used as a training facility for members of the vampire extermination unit.
実はあそこ　吸血鬼殲滅部隊の隊員を養成するための場所で
訓練を受けていない者が入ると　鬼に取り憑かれる可能性があります
Should inexperienced personnel enter, they may be possessed by a demon.
What? A demon?
鬼って
I told you, didn't I?
だから言ったでしょう
もう殲滅部隊に入る訓練は始まってるって
Your training for the extermination unit
has already begun.
次のステップに行くんですよ
We'll be moving on to the next stage.
Please follow me.
ついてきてください
地下神殿
An underground shrine?
なんで学校の地下に神殿があるんだよ
What's something like that doing beneath the school?
Well, we just call it a shrine.
神殿っていうのは　まぁ呼び名だけですけどね
かつて渋谷の地下には　川の増水を防ぐための巨大な空洞があったそうです
Long ago, there was a vast space underneath Shibuya to prevent the river from flooding.
The vampire extermination unit decided that it would become their training area.
そして　そこを吸血鬼殲滅部隊は訓練場に選んだ
Well, actually, the entire school itself is a training area for the extermination unit.
というか　学校全体が殲滅部隊の訓練場になってます
We hold a demon underground, and those unaffected by its evil energy are eventually recruited.
地下に鬼を飼って
鬼の邪気にあてられても　暴走しなかった人間を部隊にいれていく
つまりここは　壮大な人体実験のための学校というわけです
To put it simply, this school only serves as a large-scale human experiment.
Did you really believe that a normal school would exist in a world as depraved as ours?
こんな狂った時代に平和な学校が本当に存在すると思ってたんですか
ここから先は　私たち殲滅部隊が呼んだ人材か
From this point on, only those selected by the extermination unit or a demon can enter.
鬼に選ばれた者しか入ることはできません
Then Yuuji's...
じゃ　祐二君は
私たちは呼んでませんね
We didn't reach out to him.
The demon may have consumed his heart by now.
今頃　鬼に心を喰われてるかも
Wh-What happens then?
こっ　心を喰われたら　どうなっちゃうの
吸血鬼より質の悪い　理性のない人喰い鬼と化します
He'll turn into something worse than a vampire.
A mindless, murderous demon.
ですから　念入りの修練がいるわけです
This is why thorough training is required.
Especially when it comes to matters of the heart.
特に心の修練が
今回はその鬼呪装備の恐ろしさについてあなた方に知っていただ…
I wanted to show you two just how potent an Infernal Arm is—
要は鬼に負けなきゃいいんだろ
So basically, you just need to win over the demon, right?
俺には復讐のために力がいるんだよ
I need power in order to get revenge.
鬼だろうが悪魔だろうが　力が手に入るなら何でもいい
As long as it's within my reach,
I don't care if it's from a demon or a devil.
Hey, don't just walk in!
勝手に
Just observe from a distance, and don't try anything funny.
遠目で見るだけで　手は出さないでください
He'll be rescued by the extermination unit.
彼は殲滅部隊で救助しますから
Nobody's made a contract with that axe yet, right?
あの斧　まだ契約できてねぇんだろ
なら俺が頂く
Don't mind if I do!
Hey, wait!
ちょっと
もう　与一さん　月鬼ノ組に応援を呼びに行ってください
Yoichi,
please call the Moon Demon Company for backup.
There's a garrison behind this place.
この広間の奥に官舎がありますから
Right!
はい
Hand that axe over!
その斧　よこせええええええ！
That's pretty impressive.
すげぇな　おい
だがシノアの鎌よりは弱ぇ
But it's nothing compared to Shinoa's scythe.
Get out of my way.
邪魔すんじゃねぇよ
Seriously, could you be any worse at getting along?
まったく　どこまで協調性がないんですか
鬼呪装備に素手で触れると
If you touch an Infernal Arm with your bare hands,
鬼に侵蝕されてあなたも彼と同様　鬼になっちゃいますよ
you'll be possessed and end up a demon, just like him.
俺は鬼にはまけねぇよ
I'm not gonna lose to some demon.
負けますよ
You will.
You can't defeat them yet.
あなたはまだ鬼には勝てない
What?
Your heart is weak.
あなたは心が弱いから
鬼は欲望を喰らう　あなたの中にある復讐心を利用されます
Demons feed on the corrupt desires within your heart. They'll take advantage of your thirst for revenge.
That's why Lieutenant Colonel Guren won't give you an Infernal Arm,
だからあなたが圧倒的な戦闘能力を持っているにも関わらず
グレン中佐まだ鬼呪装備を与えない
despite your overwhelming combat skills.
ざけんな
Bullshit.
I'll show you right here and now that I can defeat a demon.
じゃあ　俺が鬼に負けないってことを　今証明してやるよ
ちょっ　無茶ですよ
Don't be ridiculous!
All right! It's mine now—
おっしゃ　武器を奪っ
Huh?
Yuu.
優ちゃん
どうしたの　ぼっとして
What's wrong? You were spacing out.
Hurry up and sit down.
早く坐んなよ　冷めちゃうよ
Dinner's getting cold.
そうよ　優ちゃんせっかく作ったんだから
Don't let my cooking go to waste, Yuu.
C'mon, Yuu!
優兄ィ　早く
It's really good.
美味しいよ
Y-Yeah...
Eat up while it's warm.
さあ　温かいうちにどうぞ
よかったね　みんな
Isn't this great, guys?
今日は優ちゃんが居てくれるよ
Yuu's with us today.
Yup!
うん
Yuu never comes over to play.
優兄ィ　全然来てくんないんだもん
Oh, right, Yuu.
そうだ　優ちゃん　革命はどうなったの
What happened to your revolution?
もう　忘れちゃったの
Jeez, did you forget?
You said you'd become strong and kill all the vampires,
強くなって吸血鬼殺して　ここに人間の王国作るって言ってたじゃない
and create a haven here for us.
Yeah, Yuu!
そうだよ　優兄ィ
We'll always be waiting for you.
僕らずっと待ってるんだよ
ほらほら　優ちゃん全然ご飯進んでないよ
C'mon, Yuu. You haven't touched your dinner.
That won't do, Yuu.
ダメだよ　優ちゃん
強くなるなら　ちゃんと食べないと
You need to eat if you want to grow stronger.
あ…あ
Y-Yeah.
お前ら　みんな生きてたのか
Have you guys been alive all this time?
What are you talking about?
何言ってるの　僕ら死んだに決まってるじゃん
We're all dead, of course.
そうだよ
Right?
Obviously!
決まってるじゃん
You're being a little weird today, Yuu.
今日の優兄　何か変だよ
私たちみんな吸血鬼に殺されて　優ちゃんだけ逃げたんだよ
That vampire killed us all,
and you were the only one who ran away.
ち…違う　逃げたんじゃ
N-No! I didn't run—
Yes, you did.
逃げたんだよ
おまけに　全然復讐もしてくれないし
And you haven't even avenged us.
頼むよ　優ちゃん
Come, now. Repay them for what you've lost.
殺された僕らのために復讐してよ
If you want, I'll even lend you my power.
なんなら僕が力を貸すよ
Just accept me into your heart...
優ちゃんの心に僕を受け入れてくれれば
Revenge.
復讐
That's right. Revenge.
そう　復讐だよ
Yeah...
そうだな
I need power to get my revenge.
復讐のためには力がいる
See?
でしょ
だから　早く僕を受け入れてよ
So just accept me already.
だが　てめぇは誰だ
But who are you?
ミカは　ミカはそんな奴じゃない
Mika...
Mika isn't that kind of person!
He's not like me. He wouldn't tell me
to chase after revenge!
あいつは俺と違って復讐しろとか言わねぇんだよ
He's smart, but nice to the point of stupidity—
いつも頭良くて　馬鹿みたいにみんなに優しくて
いつも全部一人で抱え込んで
someone who shouldered everything on his own...
Yuu...
優ちゃん
So who the hell are you?!
なのに　てめぇは何なんだよ
Stop, Yuu.
やめて　優ちゃん
Shut up!
黙れ
大切な家族の真似なんてしやがって
How dare you make a cheap mockery of my precious family?!
お前に俺の大切な家族の何が分かるってんだ
What the hell do you know about them?!
Oh.
あれ　俺いま何してたんだ
Huh?
What just happened?
嘘でしょう　まさか自力で戻ったんですか
No way... Did you really come back on your own?
ん　戻ったって何が
What? Come back from where?
いや　えーと　あなたは鬼に幻覚を見せられてたんです
Well, um...
A demon was feeding you hallucinations.
でも　それを意志の力だけで破って調伏しちゃった
But you managed to break free through sheer willpower and exorcised it—
all without using a contract spell.
契約呪もなしに
And that means?
つまり　どういうこと
この斧は俺のもんってことか
Is this mine now?
No, I'm afraid it's not that easy.
いえいえ　そう簡単にはいきません
There are certain procedures
to forming a contract with a demon.
鬼を使役するには手順がありますから
あなたにどの武器を与えるかも　グレン中佐が決めます
Lieutenant Colonel Guren will be the one to assign you a weapon.
でも俺は鬼に勝った
But I defeated a demon.
Well, uh...
えーとですね
グレンのバカも無視できねぇ　そうだろ
Even that dumbass Guren won't be able to ignore this, right?
あ…まあ　そうですね
Er, well... I suppose.
クラスメイトも救いましたし
And you did save your classmate...
You'll probably start coming here as of tomorrow.
明日からでもここに　この吸血鬼殲滅部隊の訓練校に通う事になるでしょう
To the vampire extermination unit's training school.
よっしゃあ
Hell yeah!
な～んて勝手に決めて　私怒られるかなぁ
I wonder if I'll get in trouble for not running this past the higher-ups.
やっとだ　やっとここまで来たぞ　ミカ
Finally...
I've come this far, Mika.
I'm gonna learn how to kill a vampire.
俺はここで　吸血鬼を殺せるようになる
ミーカー　ミーカー　ミーミーカー
Mika, Mika, Mimika.
I knew I'd find you here.
いや　やっぱりここにいましたか　報告聞きました
Did you receive the report?
It looks like they've finally found that
precious angel you've been searching for.
何でも　やっと見付かったらしいですよ
君がずっと捜していた　大切な天使君が
Unsurprisingly enough, he was being used by those corrupt humans.
思ったとおり　汚い人間に利用されてました
百夜　優一郎君がね
And by "he"...
I mean Hyakuya Yuuichirou.
Now, now.
さあさあ　あなたはどう物語を紡ぎますか
How will you weave the threads of your story,
Hyakuya Mikaela?
百夜ミカエラ君
馴染めた白　鳥がご隅　鼓動獲たツボミも
najimeta shi ni torikago sumi
Caged in the city I call home
kogoeta tsubomi no okizarigoe
A frozen bud cries silently
置き去り声　眩めた　記憶の影
kurameta kioku no kage
Turning the shadows of my memories ever darker
I need your blood
i need your blood
You really love 唱える
you need love tonight
Just as you need love tonight
足掻く　Red Light
akaku red line
We're walking a red tightrope
嗅ぎ分けた音　音と
kakiwaketa neon to
As the neon lights we leave in our wake
こじ開けたReasonが
kojiaketa reason ga
And the reasons we carved out for ourselves
ただ平行に並ぶ
tada heikou ni narabu
Run parallel
Come on break it down for me!
Come and break it down for me
come and break it down for me
A river will flow
i'll lead the way home
And I'll lead the way home
KEYがない「欲しい」でも　利害鳴る鈴
i'll lead the way home
Though the shooting stars pay no heed to us
kiganai hoshi demo
negai nasazu
Leaving our wishes unfulfilled
懺悔さえ乾いた　４拍子が　奏でた意図を辿る
negai nasazu
zange sae kawaita yogoshi ga
In a depraved world devoid of guilt
kanadetai tone nara
The tone you evoke
木漏れ日の　赤が　騒ぐ
kanadetai tone nara
Turns dusk a madder red
komorebi no aka ga sawagu
Next time, on Seraph of the End:
次回　終わりのセラフ
Vampire
Mikaela
"Vampire Mikaela."